Guide to the Rice University Dean of Engineering Records, 1951-2011 UA 115
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Dean of Engineering Records
1951-2011
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University. Office of Dean of Engineering
UA 115
83.5 Linear Feet (84 boxes)
The Dean of Engineering Records cover the years 1951 to 2011 for the Engineering School at Rice Univeristy in Houston, Texas. The records include the papers of several deans and staff. Topics include academics, research projects, faculty, and general administration.
Biographical / Historical
Engineering has been a part of Rice's curriculum since the university first opened as The Rice Institute in 1912. In those early days Rice offered courses in chemical, civil, mechanical and electrical engineering. Over the years, the engineering program grew, and in 1975 the George R. Brown School of Engineering was established. Today the school is comprised of eight academic departments and includes fourteen research institutes and centers. More than one fourth of Rice students are engineering majors.
Among the more than 100 engineering faculty are six members of the National Academy of Engineering. Virtually all undergraduate courses in engineering are taught by Ph.D. faculty. With a small student-to-faculty ratio, students in both undergraduate and graduate programs not only have easy access to professors in the classroom, but work closely with them in their labs. Departments and centers within the school of engineering take advantage of Houston's role as a center for the energy industry, medical research, space exploration, and the city's rapidly growing high-technology sector. Several departments have active industrial affiliates programs, and many research projects are undertaken with local companies. Students benefit from these relationships through collaborative research projects, summer internships, and making contacts for employment before graduation.
Scope and Contents
The Dean of Engineering Records covers the years 1951 to 2011 for the Engineering School at Rice Univeristy in Houston, Texas. The records include the papers of several deans and staff. Topics include academics, research projects, faculty, and general administration. This collections contains 83 boxes.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Restrictions on Access
Acess to this material requires permission from the Office of the Dean of Engineering. Contact the Woodson Research Center for more information. woodson@rice.edu
Provenance
The School of Engineering and the Office of the Dean of Engineering transferred this collection to the Woodson Research Center.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges
Document Types
financial records; letters (correspondence); minutes (administrative records)
Subjects (Persons)
Brotzen, Franz R.; Griffis, Levan
Subjects (Corporations)
Rice University. Office of Dean of Engineering; Rice University
- Series 1: General Files, 1957-1999
  Scope and Contents Note
  This series contains a selection of items labeled "General" files by the office staff of the Dean of Engineering.
  - Scholarships/fellowships A-D, 1959-1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Scholarships/fellowships DuPont, 1966-1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Scholarships/fellowships E-W, 1951-1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Professional and non-academic personnel, appointments and terminations A-F, 1962-1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Professional and non-academic personnel, appointments and terminations G, 1957-1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Professional and non-academic personnel, appointments and terminations H-O, 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Professional and non-academic personnel, appointments and terminations P-R, 1962-1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Professional and non-academic personnel, appointments and terminations S-Y, 1964-1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - General Files, ASSE (American Society of Engineering Education), Budget, NSF, Administrative Files, 1976-1994 (Box 2)
  - Dow Chemical - RESC (Rice Engineering Societies Council Career Fair), 1963-1992 (Box 3)
  - RESC - Correspondence files, 1964-1994 (Box 4)
  - Performance evaluation of faculty - EESI (Energy and Envioronmental Systems Institute), 1989-1997 (Box 5)
  - EESI - Environmental Science and Engineering, EPA Site Unit, 1986-1997 (Box 6)
  - Budgets - George R. Rupp resignation, 1985-1995 (Box 7)
  - Laser Research - Space planning, reassignments, 1980-1996 (Box 8)
  - Degrees granted data - Posse, 1978-1998 (Box 9)
  - Postdoc Fellows/Research Associates - Annual Texas Dean Meeting, 1973-1995 (Box 10)
  - Texas State Board of Registration for Professional Engineers - Royal Thai Military Academy visitors, 1972-1999 (Box 11)
  - Rupp, George, Rice President - University Relations, Rupp-Ad Hoc Committee, 1960-1995 (Box 12)
  - University relations research development - ASCE Convention, 1976-1996 (Box 13)
  - Budget 1980 - Brown Budget, 1977-1996 (Box 14)
  - American Society for Engineering Education - Brown Engineering Development Fund - Report to Development, 1969-1998 (Box 15)
  - Brown Committee - Engineering Dean Institute, 1976-1997 (Box 16)
  - Engineering Major, non-science Foundation Course - Fundraising for Computational Engineering, 1982-1995 (Box 17)
  - REAP, Fundraising - Human Resources, 1980-1995 (Box 18)
  - Human Resources Job Descriptions - NASA General Information, 1971-1995 (Box 19)
  - National Institutes of Health - NASA General Information, 1981-1995 (Box 20)
  - Subseries A: ABET, 1955-2003
    The sub series contains papers related to the Accreditation Board for Engineering and Technology, known as ABET.
    - ABET, 1990-1991 - ABET Miscellaneous, 1990-1995 (Box 20)
    - ABET meeting - Questionnaire for Review of Engineering Programs electrical engineering, 1955-200 (Box 21)
    - Questionnaire for Review of Engineering programs, Civil Engineering - ABET Annual report, 1975-1989 (Box 22)
    - Self Study Questionnaire for review of engineering programs, Civil Engineering - ABET annual report, 1975-1989 (Box 23)
    - ABET Department Interviews Summary - ABET Annual reports, circa 1970-1996 (Box 24)
    - ABET Request for Extension of accreditation - ABET certificates, 1972-1991 (Box 25)
    - ABET visit, 1988-2003 (Box 26)
  - Subseries B: Educational Outcome Reports: education, teaching and assessment, 1976-2001
    The sub series contains papers related to assessments of teaching and learning at Rice University.
    - Learning and Teaching - Conference notes, 1998-2001 (Box 26)
    - CAAM assessments - Cain project, 1976-2001 (Box 27)
  - Subseries C: Sydney Burrus Papers, 1966-2001
    - Elec [Electrical engineering] - Bennett, John, -- ELEC, 1976-2001 (Box 27)
      The sub series contains papers related to Sydney Burrus, dean of engineering.
    - Bodner, Sol - Westoff, James C., 1997-2001 (Box 28)
    - Colloquiums - Annual Reports to the President, 1982-1998 (Box 29)
    - Annual reports to the President - DENG - Chair's Manual, 1966-1997 (Box 30)
  - Subseries D: Hardy Bourland Papers, 1966-2001
    Lecturer Emeritus on Electrical and Computer Engineering. Hardy Bourland came to Rice in 1961 from General Dynamics, where he was a senior aero systems engineer. A registered professional engineer, Bourland has served the university in several capacities--as executive director of the Rice Engineering Design and Development Institute, as assistant to the dean for student development and as associate director of the Biomedical Engineering Laboratory. (B.S., 1955 Texas Technological College; S.M.E.E., 1957, Massachusetts Institute of Technology).)
    - Bourland Bio Med Lab research - Jerimac T. Ratliff, 1966-1997 (Box 30)
    - Audio Prosthesis Draft 1975 - Correspondence 1988, 1975-2000 (Box 31)
    - Correspondence 1988 - Dean's Council 1994, 1988-1994 (Box 32)
    - Employment Policy 1994-1995 - CEB space proposal and budget, 1995-1996 (Box 33)
    - CEB Networking - Budget miscellaneous, 1996-2001 (Box 34)
    - Budget miscellaneous - Controller's Office, 1978-1995 (Box 35)
    - TX A and M/Engr Education - Dean VP report (Gifts), 1988-1998 (Box 36)
- Series 2: Faculty, 1969-2005
  - Subseries A: Terminated Faculty, 1983-2005 (Box 36-45)
    This sub series contains administrative files for terminated faculty. Reasons for termination include lack of funding, failure to attain tenure, resignation, disciplinary action or death.
  - Subseries B: Faculty Correspondence, 1969-1994
    The sub series contains papers related to REDDI Proposals and the School of Engineering's departmental correspondence.
    - Cont. Envi; 1969-1973 - MEMS, 1969-1987 (Box 45)
    - Correspondence: A – Chemical Engineering, 1969-1985 (Box 46)
    - Correspondence: A – Chemical Engineering, 1970-1987 (Box 47)
    - Pharr, George: Promotion Withdrawn – CAAM Old Correspondence, 1990-1994 (Box 48)
    - Comp Sci Old Correspondence – GRB General Info, 1986-1994 (Box 49)
    - Computer Print Out – NSCH 106 BDM Corp/Margrave "Laser Pyrolysis of Materials", 1982-1987 (Box 50)
    - ECHE113 EPR/McIntire "Dynamic Material Properties of…Complex Fluids" – Time Energy Corporation, 1983-1987 (Box 51)
- Series 3: Budget, 1968-1998
  The series contains papers related to the budget for the School of Engineering.
  - Budget (Folder 1 of 2) – Budget Forms: The 7 Departments, 1986-1988 (Box 51)
  - Budget (Folder 1 of 3) – Faculty Reports to the President (Folder 2 of 2), 1984-1989 (Box 52)
  - Industrial Engineering: Ad Hoc Committee – GSS Budgets, 1968-1998 (Box 53)
  - H. Bourland Correspondence – Fund and Budget Detail (Folder 1 of 4), 1993-1998 (Box 54)
  - Fund and Budget Detail (Folder 2 of 4) – Fund and Budget Detail (Folder 4 of 4), 1998 (Box 55)
- Series 4: Michael Carroll Period, 1971-1996
  The series contains papers related to Michael Carroll, Dean of Engineering.
  - Ford Foundation Honors Course – Self-study report, 1988-1995 (Box 55)
  - ECPD Accreditation (Folder 1 of 2) – Emails (Folder 3 of 3), 1971-1996 (Box 56)
  - Chair's Manual: CENG – Faculty Citation Survey, 1987-1996 (Box 57)
- Series 5: Administrative (includes professional organizations, internal programs and projects) ,1975-1998
  - Subseries A: American Society for Engineering Education (ASEE), 1986-1995
    The sub series contains papers related to the American Society for Engineering Education, known as ASEE.
    - ASEE – ASEE G.E. Senior Research Award Committee (Folder 1 of 2), 1986-1995 (Box 57)
    - ASEE G.E. Senior Research Award Committee (Folder 2 of 2) – ASEE, 1995 (Box 58)
  - Subseries B: American Board of Clinical Engineers (ABCE), 1975-1977
    The series contains papers related to the American Board of Clinical Engineers, known as ABCE.
    - BCE – AAMI relationship – ABCE "1000", 1975-1977 (Box 58)
  - Subseries C: Advisory Council, 1983-1990
    The sub series contains papers related to the advisory council for the School of Engineering.
    - Charter and Organization of Advisory Council – Advisory Council Meeting, 1983-1984 (Box 58)
    - Advisory Council – Advisory Council Meeting, 1984-1987 (Box 59)
    - Advisory Council Meeting (Folder 1 of 3) – Advisory Council, 1988-1990 (Box 60)
  - Subseries D: Minority Affairs, 1980-1998
    The sub series contains papers related to programs and correspondence regarding minority students.
    - GEM (Folder 1 of 2) – NACME, 1983-1998 (Box 60)
    - NACME – Minority Affairs: General, 1980-1983 (Box 61)
    - Minorities Program General Correspondence – POSSE, 1996 (Box 62)
    - POSSE retreat – NACME/POSSE, 1996-1998 (Box 63)
  - Subseries E: Engineering Proposals up to 1991, 1987-1996
    The sub series contains papers related to proposals for the School of Engineering up to the year 1991.
    - BIOE – CITI Budget, 1987-1992 (Box 63)
    - CITI Steering Committee – CRPC, 1996 (Box 64)
  - Subseries F: Computational Engineering Building, 1994-1996
    The series contains papers related to the Computational Engineering Building, also known as Duncan Hall.
    - CEB Groundbreaking and Planning – CEB Correspondence File No. 3, 1994-1996 (Box 64)
  - Subseries G: Scholarship Info
    The sub series contains papers related to scholarships available to students of the School of Engineering.
    - Index of Scholarships – AAUWEF – Brown and Root (Box 64)
    - Brown Awards (Folder 1 of 4) – National Merit Scholarships – Western Electric Fund (Box 65)
  - Subseries H: Corporate Affiliates
    The series contains papers related to the corporate affiliates of the School of Engineering.
    - Corporate Affiliates Programs – CAPS Comp Sci: Digital Equipment Company – Kubota (Box 65)
    - CAPS Comp Sci: Mas Par Computer Corporation, Super computer systems corps – CAP at other schools (Box 66)
  - Subseries I: Publications and Photos
    The series contains various brochures, publications, and photos from the School of Engineering.
    - Engineering Division Brochure Overview 1993 – Publications: General Rice University (Box 66)
    - Publications: General GRB (Folder 1 of 2) – Publications: CENG (Box 67)
- Series 6: Addenda, 1960-1983
  - Recommendations: Engineering Space Modifications, January 15, 1960 (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Duplicate Drawings- Engineering Area (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - L.B. Ryon Building (G.R. Brown), 1961-1962 (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - National Science Foundation, Grant 13823; Final Report, January 31, 1962 (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Engineering Building Planning Committee; To be appointed by Kenneth Pitzer, Febuary 1962 (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Advisory Council in Engineering, 1966-1969 (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - Advisory Council in Engineering: Meeting, March 17, 1970 (Box 68, Folder 7)
  - Advisory Council in Engineering: Meeting, November 12, 1970 (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Advisory Council in Engineering: Meeting, April 1, 1971 (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Advisory Council in Engineering: Meeting, November 18, 1971 (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - Advisory Council in Engineering: Report, October 25, 1972 (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Advisory Council in Engineering: Meeting, October 25, 1972 (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - Advisory Council in Engineering: Report, November 28, 1973 (Box 69, Folder 6)
  - Advisory Council in Engineering: Meeting, November 28, 1973 (Box 69, Folder 7)
  - Advisory Council in Engineering, 1971-1974 (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - Advisory Council in Engineering: Meeting, November 6, 1974 (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - Advisory Council in Engineering: Meeting, November 12, 1975 (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - Advisory Council in Engineering (Originals), November 12, 1975 (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Advisory Council in Engineering, 1975 (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - Advisory Council in Engineering Membership List (Box 70, Folder 6)
  - Rice Engineering Alumni Award, 1966-1969 (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - Rice Engineering Alumni Award, 1974-1975 (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - Rice Engineering Alumni Award, 1975-1976 (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - Rice Engineering Alumni Award, 1976-1977 (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - Rice Engineering Alumni Award, 1977-1978 (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - Rice Engineering Alumni Award, 1978-1979 (Box 71, Folder 6)
  - Engineering Alumni- Supporting Members; $10 to $250, 1980 (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - Engineering Alumni- Lifetime Supporting Members; $250 or more, 1980 (Box 71, Folder 8)
  - Engineering Alumni Fund Drive (Letter on Memory); $250 Lifetime Membership, 1981 (Box 71, Folder 9)
  - Engineering Alumni Fund Drive; $25 to $250, 1981 (Box 71, Folder 10)
  - Rice Engineering Alumni; Letterhead (Box 71, Folder 11)
  - Rice Engineering Alumni Board, 1975-1976 (Box 71, Folder 12)
  - Engineering Alumni; Board, List of Lifetime Supporting Members, Misc. (Box 71, Folder 13)
  - University Council, 1977-1980 (Box 71, Folder 14)
  - Faculty Council Meetings, 1975-1980 (Box 71, Folder 15)
  - Mechanics, 1978-1983 (Box 72, Folder 1)
  - Effective Moduli, 1980 (Box 72, Folder 2)
  - Brown Committee for Counselling of Freshman and Sophomore Engineers, 1970 (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - Junior Engineering Technical Society, 1973 (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - Brown Com. Film on "Engineering at Rice", 1972-1973 (Box 72, Folder 5)
  - Brown Committee Engineering Summer School, 1974-1975 (Box 72, Folder 6)
  - NSPE Scholarship (Brown Engr. Development Committee), 1973-1975 (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - Summer Engineering School, 1977 (Box 72, Folder 8)
  - Rice Summer Program Brown Committee, 1976 (Box 72, Folder 9)
  - Engineering Development Committee Student Evaluation of Summer Program, 1976 (Box 72, Folder 10)
  - George R. Brown Undergrad Engr. Department Grant Com., 1976 (Box 72, Folder 11)
  - Brown Engr. Development Com. Student Scholarships and Merit Awards, 1969-1970 (Box 72, Folder 12)
  - Brown Engineering Committee Minutes, 1971-1976 (Box 72, Folder 13)
  - Brown Engr. Development Com., 1969-1970 (Box 72, Folder 14)
  - Brown Engr. Development Com., 1971-1973 (Box 72, Folder 15)
  - Brown Engineering Development Fund Budget, 1969-1980 (Box 72, Folder 16)
  - Brown Engr. Development Com. Student Scholarships and Merit Awards, 1971-1973 (Box 72, Folder 17)
  - Brown, George R. Person, 1980 (Box 72, Folder 18)
  - Brown Engr. Development Committee, 1973-1974 (Box 72, Folder 19)
  - Brown Engineering Development Committeee Recruitment Letters, 1973 (Box 72, Folder 20)
  - George R. Brown School of Engineering, 1972-1975 (Box 72, Folder 21)
  - Brown Development Committee Correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 72, Folder 22)
  - George R. Brown School of Engineering Summary (First Year), 1975-1976 (Box 72, Folder 23)
  - Materials Science Volume II, 1976 (Box 72, Folder 24)
  - Donations toward School of Engr., 1980-1983 (Box 72, Folder 25)
  - Engineering Day (Brown Engr. Development Com.) (Box 72, Folder 26)
- Series 7: Addenda, 1980s-2008 (Box 73)
  - Advanced Micro Devices, 2000 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - American Leadership Forum, 2007 (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - M.D. Anderson Cancer Center, 2003 (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - Animal facilities, 2001 (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - Army HPC Center, 1999 (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - Baker Institute, 1993-97 (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - Baylor College of Medicine, 1989, 1990s (Box 73, Folder 7)
  - Beckman Foundation, 2003 (Box 73, Folder 8)
  - Bioengineering proposal, 1981-82, 90 (Box 73, Folder 9)
  - Biomedical Engineering Laboratory, 1990s-2002 (Box 73, Folder 10-11)
  - Biosciences building, 1987-92 (Box 73, Folder 12)
  - Biosciences Building, 1987-1992 (Box 73, Folder 13)
  - Biosciences Building, 1987-1992 (Box 73, Folder 14)
  - Biotechnology, 2002 (Box 73, Folder 15)
  - Bioterrorism, 2002 (Box 73, Folder 16)
  - Boeing Co. (Box 73, Folder 17)
  - Bonner lab, 1994-97 (Box 73, Folder 18)
  - Bremen University, 1998-2004 (Box 73, Folder 19)
  - Budgets, 2000 2001 (Box 73, Folder 20)
  - Budget, 2003 (Box 73, Folder 21)
  - Center for Advanced Applications for Technology in Education, 2000-01 (Box 73, Folder 22)
  - Center for Biological Environmental Nanotechnology, 2001-03 (Box 73, Folder 23)
  - Center for Computational Geosciences, 1995-96 (Box 73, Folder 24)
  - Center for High Performance Software Research, 2000 (Box 73, Folder 25)
  - Center for Nanoscale Science Technology, 1999-2002 (Box 73, Folder 26)
  - Center for Nanoscale Science Technology, Evans Attwell Fellowship, 2002 (Box 73, Folder 27)
  - Center for Research on Parallel Computation, 1996, 98 (Box 73, Folder 28)
  - Center for Technology in Teaching Learning, 1995-97, 2000 (Box 73, Folder 29)
  - Centers (Box 73, Folder 30)
  - Chairs' Leadership Workshop, 2004, 08 (Box 73, Folder 31)
  - Chemical Engineering, 1997-98 (Box 73, Folder 32)
  - Chemical Engineering, 2000-04 (Box 73, Folder 33)
  - Chemical Engineering Ad Hoc Advisory Cmte., 1998-2000 (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - China-India-US Workshop (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - Christopher Columbus Fellowship Foundation, 2003 (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - City of Houston project (UH/TSU), 2000-01 (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - Civil Engineering, 1995/96, 2003-04 (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - Civil Engineering Advisory Group, 1983/84, 2000s (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - Civil Engineering Strategic Plan, 1996, 2000 (Box 74, Folder 7)
  - Civil Engineering/Environmental Engineering merger, 2001 (Box 74, Folder 8)
  - Civil Environmental Engineering, 2003-04 (Box 74, Folder 9)
  - Comparable Studies Cmte., 1999-2001 (Box 74, Folder 10)
  - Comparables Study, 2000 (Box 74, Folder 11)
  - Computational Applied Mathematics, 1990s (Box 74, Folder 12)
  - Computational Applied Mathematics, 2000s (Box 74, Folder 13)
  - Computational Information Science Engineering at Rice, 1990s (Box 74, Folder 14)
  - Computer Information Technology Institute, 1995-97 (Box 74, Folder 15)
  - Computer Information Technology Institute, 1997-99 (Box 74, Folder 16)
  - Computer Information Technology Institute, 2000-03 (Box 74, Folder 17)
  - Computer Science, 1996-99 (Box 74, Folder 18)
  - Computer Science, 1997-99 (Box 74, Folder 19)
  - Computer Science, 2000-04 (Box 74, Folder 20)
  - Computer Systems Laboratory, 1999 (Box 74, Folder 21)
  - Conflict of interest, 1995-97 (Box 74, Folder 22)
  - Consortium of Financing Higher Education, 1998, 2000-03 (Box 74, Folder 23)
  - Consortium of Financing Higher Education, 1990s (Box 74, Folder 23)
  - Subseries: Correspondence
    - Incoming 1999, Jan-Sept (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Incoming 1999, Oct-Dec (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Outgoing 2000, Feb-Oct (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Outgoing 2000, Nov-June 2001 (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Incoming 2000, July-Dec (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - Outgoing 2001, Aug-Dec (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - Incoming 2001, Jan-Apr (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - Outgoing 2002, Jan-Apr (Box 75, Folder 9)
    - Outgoing 2002, May-Dec (Box 75, Folder 10)
    - Outgoing 2003, Jan-July (Box 75, Folder 11)
    - Outgoing 2003, Aug-Dec (Box 75, Folder 12)
    - Outgoing 2004, Jan-Mar (Box 75, Folder 13)
    - Outgoing 2004, Apr-Dec (Box 75, Folder 14)
  - Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency (DARPA), 1997 (Box 75, Folder 15)
  - Dell Compter Corp., 1999 (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Dept. of Defense Advanced Applied Technology Demonstration Facility, 1992-93 (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - Dept. of Energy, 1980s-90s (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Digital Signal Processing 30 year celebration, 1998 (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - Dupont, 1988-96 (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - Earth Systems Institute, 1987-93 (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - Electrical Computer Engineering, 1990s (Box 76, Folder 7)
  - Electrical Computer Engineering, 1997-2000s (Box 76, Folder 8)
  - Electrical Computer Engineering Corporate Affiliates, 1990s (Box 76, Folder 9)
  - Engineering Foundation, 1994 (Box 76, Folder 10)
  - Engineering gender issues, 2003-04 (Box 76, Folder 11)
  - Engineering research funding, 1980s (Box 76, Folder 12)
  - Engineering Energy Systems Institute (Box 76, Folder 13-15)
  - EESI space requirements, 1993 (Box 76, Folder 16)
  - Environmental Engineering, 1994-99 (Box 76, Folder 17)
  - Environmental Space Engineering, 1990s (Box 76, Folder 18-19)
  - ES (Box 76, Folder 20)
  - ES (Box 76, Folder 21)
  - Faculty (Box 76, Folder 22)
  - Infrastructure issues, 1996 (Box 76, Folder 23)
  - Institute of Biosciences Bioengineering, 1990s (Box 76, Folder 24)
  - Keck Center for Computational Biology, 1989 (Box 76, Folder 25)
  - Mechanical Engineering Materials Science, 1990s-2000s (Box 76, Folder 26-27)
  - Program development assessment, 1998 (Box 76, Folder 28)
  - Provost, 1997, 99 (Box 76, Folder 30)
  - Restructuring plan, 1997 (Box 76, Folder 30)
  - Rice Engineering Alumni, 1980s (Box 76, Folder 31)
  - Rice Quantum Institute, 1994-99 (Box 76, Folder 32)
  - Stanford study of GRB, 1997 (Box 76, Folder 33)
  - [Dept. of] Statistics, 1996-2000s (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Status of GRB, 2001 (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Strategic goals, 1999 (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Strategic plan, 1997-98 (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - US/EU Consortium, 1995 (Box 77, Folder 5)